This is fun, it's like we're going on a road trip.
好像在兜風一樣，真開心
You're right.
對啊
Why don't we sing a song together?
大家一起來唱歌吧
Chief.
主任
This stupid girl
這個蠢女人
is getting field trips
把業務和遠足混為一談了
Stupid girl?
蠢女人？
As part of my job,
我只是把這當作業務的一環
I came along to see rice plastic production site.
陪同各位前往 米塑膠的製造現場而已
You can't make me sing songs on the way back.
可不打算在回程 和大家一起唱歌
Sure, but let's try to have a good time.
別這樣嘛，開心點
About rice plastic...
米塑膠
I thought maybe we can use it for the Temp's Lunch Box.
不曉得能不能用在派遣便當上
But it'd be hard if each piece cost 100 yen.
單價要壓在100圓很困難吧
Not him.
那傢伙不行
He doesn't understand.
他不理解公司這個組織
For this project,...
這企劃案由你來處理
Don't tell Satonaka yet.
這件事先別跟里中說
Also,
還有
watch out for Haruko Omae.
要小心大前春子
Oh!
嚇死人
Don't glare at me through the mirror!
別透過鏡子瞪我啊
You're scary.
很恐怖
You usually talk nonsense nonstop
平常愛說廢話的東海林主任
but today you're so quiet that I thought you were dead.
今天非常安靜 我還想說是不是死了
I am alive. Don't think I'm dead.
我還活著，別隨便咒人死
You seem down, Shoji.
東海林先生很沒精神呢
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
Nothing.
沒什麼
Don't do your weird exercise in the car.
別在車子裡做奇怪的體操
I'm checking safety. Problem?
這是在確認安全，有問題嗎？
There are no cars around. No way you'll get into an accident.
這條路上只有我們這台車 能發生什麼事故
If you're not happy, get out of my car.
有意見的話就下車
Just start the car.
好了，快開車吧
How much longer do you need to check?
你是要確認到什麼時候？
The car's not moving.
車子動不了
Is it broken?
故障了嗎？
What's going on?
搞什麼啊
What do we do?
沒事吧？
What happened?
這沒辦法了
Oh, Haruko, maybe you are
如果是春子前輩
a certified auto mechanic, too?
一定有汽車修理士的證照吧
Oh yeah.
對喔
You're an elevator mechanic.
畢竟你有修電梯的執照嘛
This should be easy.
車子根本小事一樁
You can repair this, right?
大前小姐一定會修理吧
Haruko?
前輩
Please.
拜託你了
Hurry up, Turtleneck.
快點修好啊，套頭毛衣女
- Hey. - Be quiet.
-喂 -吵死了
Don't talk to me.
請別跟我說話
You've done something irreparable.
話說回來
That can't be right.
不可能的對吧？
For Haruko, nothing is impossible.
春子前輩的字典裡 是沒有不可能這個字的
But you don't need to take apart the car.
但這又不是解體
Just fix what's wrong with it.
只要車子能動就好
Hey.
喂
Are you sure you're okay?
你真的沒問題嗎？
Do you really have a certificate in this?
你真的有證照嗎？
No.
我沒有
Problem?
有問題嗎？
What?
-什麼？ -啥
I never said I had a certificate.
我從來都沒說過我有證照
So what?
有問題嗎？
Omae...
我說你啊…
Chief.
主任
I've never fixed a car.
我沒有修過車
But as you can see,
但如各位所見
I've done everything I could do.
我已經無計可施了
Unfortunately,
很遺憾
it's six o'clock, so I'm leaving.
已經六點了，我先失陪了
Hey! Clearly you don't think this is unfortunate.
等等，你這是遺憾的樣子嗎？
You'll just leave this and go home?
你想把車子放著就逃嗎？
Please call JAF.
請叫JAF路面服務
Say that before you take the entire car apart.
這種事給我在 把車子弄得亂七八糟前說啊
Hey! Wait!
給我站住
- So there are things... - You're in charge of this.
-你給我把所有零件裝回去 -竟然有春子前輩做不到的事
Haruko can't do.
你給我負責
- That's a company car! - Proud employees will have a fall.
那可是公司的車，誰要負責
Companies won't survive without temp workers now.
在這個時代，公司一旦少了 派遣員工就無法正常運作
For example, Haruko Omae here.
例如這位大前春子
"Impossible" and "social skills" are not in her dictionary.
她的字典裡沒有 「不可能」和「溝通技巧」
She shuts down all troublesome relationships
排除一切複雜的人際關係
and disappears after three months when her contract ends.
隨著三個月的契約期滿
But why did the super temp worker Haruko Omae
但是仍無人知曉
decide to be a non-permanent employee?
超級派遣員大前春子
That's still a mystery.
為何選擇踏上非正職員工一途
"The Pride Of The Temp"
派遣員的品格
"A marriage proposal to a temp!?"
〝對派遣員求婚？〞
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I want to get myself fired up.
我也想振作精神
Let's do our best, Mori!
小森，加油喔
With Temp's Lunch Box.
派遣便當
Why don't you join us, Mr Ogasawara?
小笠原先生也一起來吧？
Would it be good for my back?
這對腰痛有效嗎？
Does that mean I should also do this?
這種空氣般的動作，我也來吧
Let's do Omae Exercise together, Chief.
主任也來吧，大前體操
No, thanks.
我就不用了
You can continue, but can I have your attention?
請各位邊做體操邊聽我說
For Temp's Lunch Box,
派遣便當
I think it's important to hear the temp workers' opinions.
最重要的還是 了解派遣員的意見
Let's do a questionnaire.
所以來發問卷吧
We'll set the menu and price according to that.
以此做為 設定價格和菜色的參考
What do you think?
怎麼樣？
Stop copying me.
請勿抄襲
Don't give my exercise a name
別替我想的體操命名
or copy my movement!
也別跟著我做
Okay, the exercise.
是在說體操啊
Good morning, Marketing Section.
早安，行銷課的各位
What's up, Shoji?
東海林先生，怎麼了？
About the lunch box project
關於派遣便當的企劃
you guys are no longer in charge.
跟你們已經無關了，收手吧
I'll be in charge on this, representing Sales Division.
這份企劃將由代表營業部的我
Again?
又來了啊？
You said again?
什麼？又來？
This was Mori's idea.
這可是小森的企劃
I can't let a temp worker be in charge of the final presentation.
最重要的最終發表 怎麼能交給一個派遣員來？
Sorry about that, Ken.
就是這樣，抱歉啦，小賢
You don't mind, right?
可以吧？
- But... - By the way, Ken...
-但是… -小賢
we had quite a day yesterday, didn't we?
昨天還真是不得了啊
Good for you, Turtleneck, because you can teleport.
套頭毛衣女 會瞬間移動所以沒差
We were in trouble after you left.
但那之後我們可辛苦了
JAF was shocked.
JAF的人也嚇到了
This is a director's order.
喂，這是部長命令
Come with me.
跟我來
Director's order?
部長命令？
She's going to help me out on the project that I'm promoting.
要找她來幫忙企劃推進專案
I'm the chief.
主任是我
Don't ignore me.
我說過別無視我
Omae...
大前小姐
please go and see.
總之你先過去吧
Okay.
是
I'm your boss now.
聽好了，主任是我
I'll straight up your twisted temp ideas.
我會好好矯正 你那扭曲的派遣劣根性
Chief Shoji.
東海林主任
You're obedient.
你還真老實
You can tell me that
這些事
after you get your twisted headpiece straightened.
請等你彎彎曲曲的假髮 燙直後再來談
As I said, this isn't a headpiece!
這可不是假髮
Did you say I should get it straightened?
你剛剛是不是還說了離子燙？
That's the word I never wants to hear.
「直髮」可是我的禁語啊
Mori.
森
I'm sorry.
抱歉
It's fine.
沒關係
You don't need to apologise.
主任你不需要道歉
This won't work, Miyashita. Do it again.
宮下，這樣業績不會成長的 重寫一次
What's going on with the Mitsuboshi Bento chains?
高橋 三星便當連鎖店如何了？
They're putting together a quote for us now.
剛才要求他們交估價表了
I'm waiting for them.
等他們聯絡
Don't just wait. Go and negotiate to lower the price.
還等什麼等，直接過去了 或多或少都給我殺點價
Five days until the presentation.
距離發表只剩五天了
Okay.
是
- This is finished. - That was so fast.
-統計完了 -動作很快嘛
I thought you'd say no to this.
我以為你肯定會拒絕的
I was curious to see whose side you would take.
但我也對你會成為誰的夥伴 感到很大的興趣
We temps only does what we're told to do.
派遣員工只是按照指示在做事
We don't take sides.
不是任何人的夥伴
I see.
這樣啊
Anyway, the executives love this project.
上頭很中意這個企劃
So it has to be perfect.
可不能做出半吊子的成果
I'm counting on you.
靠你們了
Shoji.
東海林
Can I talk to you?
過來一下
An arranged marriage?
相親嗎？
For me?
我嗎？
She's the daughter of Taiyo Bank's president.
是太陽銀行董事長的千金
We talked to them at the golf competition the other day.
你們上次在高爾夫大賽上 有說過話吧？
Excuse me.
我先拜見一下
She is the president's daughter?
這位就是董事長千金啊？
She is interested in you,
據說對你一見鍾情
or rather, in your jokes and wants to see you.
她想跟你聊聊 所以就安排了這場相親
You'll see her, right?
你一定會去跟對方見面吧
It's Taiyo Bank.
畢竟是太陽銀行嘛
Thank you.
謝謝
That's awesome, Shoji.
太好了，東海林
Hey, Satonaka.
里中
Are you okay about him taking the project?
那個企劃讓給他沒關係嗎？
Yeah.
沒關係
Now he might possibly marry the daughter of an executive.
現在還要跟董事長千金談親
He's moving up in the world.
你們差距越來越大了
Shoji.
東海林先生
Our team would like to help with your presentation.
行銷課也會協助發表會的
We can have 1,000 people take the questionnaire.
我們打算收集一千份的問卷
You don't have to do that.
小賢，不用勉強自己
But I want to.
我沒有勉強啊
You'll go for the girl?
你要去相親嗎？
Well...
對
it was suggested by the director,
畢竟是部長介紹的
so I can't say no.
怎麼能拒絕
Turtleneck.
套頭毛衣女
I'm still on my break.
現在還是休息時間
In that case...
那不然…
I just want to talk.
這雖然只是閒聊啦
I...
我…
I got a possible proposal for an arranged marriage.
要去相親了
I don't know what to do.
不知道該怎麼辦才好
Any reactions?
你也給點反應啊
So it's not too late.
現在還來得及呢
What?
什麼？
If you'd like...
不介意的話
before you see her...
在相親之前
this.
這個
Please call.
請一定要打電話
Could this be...
這該不會…
her number?
是手機號碼？
It must be.
一定是
She's finally opening up to me.
那傢伙終於對我敞開心房了
What? Why do you look sad?
小賢，你怎麼一臉感傷？
Open it.
快點看看吧
Oh yeah.
好
What's this?
這是啥？
It's one o'clock. Get out my way, I'm making tea.
一點了，我要泡茶，請借過
Hey.
喂
Don't you ever talk to me about hair straightening.
不准再跟我提到燙直的話題
- I... - Shoji.
-我可是… -東海林先生
I tried it before.
我之前就燙過了
- Shoji! - It didn't work.
-但完全燙不直
For the Temp's Lunch Box,
為了派遣便當
let's do what we can do as a team.
我們行銷課
I upset Chief Shoji and now I'm off his project.
因為東海林主任生氣了 所以我被趕出專案了
What?
咦？
He told me to get out when I used the word "straight" again.
我又提到了直髮
Alright.
那…
Please help us make the questionnaire, then.
大前小姐也來幫忙收集問卷吧
Our goal is to get answers from 1,000 temp workers.
目標是一千名派遣員工的意見
Chief.
主任
Why are you doing this much for Chief Shoji?
你為什麼要 幫東海林主任這麼多？
Even if you get along with him, I'd never want to be his friend.
不管你們感情多好 我一輩子都不可能和他當朋友
Calm down.
好了…
Mr Shoji is...
東海林主任
not a bad person.
也不是什麼壞人
He gets blinded when his promotion is on the line, though.
只是為了出人頭地 而不顧身邊的人
That's what we call a bad person.
這種人就是壞人啊
Excuse me...
那個…
but why are you doing this?
主任為什麼？
Mori.
森
Can I be a bit selfish about this?
你能聽我
I want to make
我…
products that make people happy when they eat.
想要做出讓吃的人 感到幸福的食品
That's why I joined this company.
所以才進了這間公司
This project reminds me of why I wanted to join the company.
在思考這個企劃的時候
Temp's Lunch Box
派遣便當
is exactly what I've been wanting to do.
正是這樣的企劃
It doesn't matter who does the presentation.
無論誰負責發表都沒關係
The most important things is to make it happen.
最重要的是要讓企劃實現
So please
請你們幫幫我吧
Sure.
好的
Let's do the questionnaire.
來發問卷吧
Omae, anything you want to say?
大前小姐
You sound like an essay written by an elementary school kid.
這種動機 簡直就像小學生的作文
Working at a company isn't that easy.
公司可沒有這麼簡單
But if it's my job, I'll do it.
但既然是業務就沒辦法了
Thank you.
麻煩你了
Chief Satonaka is a wonderful person.
里中主任真是個優秀的人
- Okay. - Really.
沒事
I won't be distracted anymore.
我已經沒有別念了
I'm very happy that I get to work under a boss like him.
能在這種上司底下工作 真是太好了
There are only two types of employees.
世界上只有兩種員工
First,
第一
the type that works for promotions.
為了出人頭地工作的員工
Second,
第二
the type that works for others.
為了別人工作的員工
Chief Shoji must be the first type.
第一種是東海林主任
The second type is liked by their subordinates
第二種是會被下屬喜歡
but the company treats them like idiots.
卻被公司當笨蛋的人
I can't bear to look at them.
做事拖泥帶水讓人看不下去
We're on a ship made of mud.
也就是我們已經上了泥船
Made of mud?
泥船？
I hope that until our contract ends,
希望至少在契約結束前
the ship stays afloat.
不要沉船
"Temp's Lunch Box"
（派遣便當）
What are you doing, Shoji?
東海林，怎麼了？
Counting steps to your promotion?
在想要怎樣才能出人頭地嗎？
Yeah, sure.
算是吧
It doesn't make sense to me.
我還是不能接受
After all, the project belongs to...
這份企劃果然…
Oh well...
算了
we can't go against our director.
你也無法違逆部長吧
If the presentation goes well, maybe you'll be a section chief.
發表順利的話 你就要升課長了吧？
You'll then marry a daughter of a bank executive.
然後跟銀行千金結婚
Not only a section chief,
部長他…
but maybe even an executive?
一定會很重用你
Sure.
對
I'll do my best.
我會加油的
"Questionnaire on temp's lunch"
（派遣員工午餐調查問卷）
"What's your favourite side dish?"
（喜歡的菜色是什麼？）
"How much do you want to spend on a lunch box?"
（願意購買多少錢的便當？）
Where they eat their lunch is also very important.
在哪裡吃便當也很重要呢
Some might eat alone at their desk
是一個人在辦公桌吃
while others might go to a park with friends.
或是在公園和朋友邊聊邊吃
Yeah.
這樣啊
- Can you add that, too? - Sure.
大前小姐，也請加上這個問題
Omae isn't good at questionnaires.
大前小姐不適合去發問卷呢
Hey.
別說了
Why wouldn't I be good at it?
我哪裡不適合？
You have an intense aura.
氣場太強了
- And you look scary. - Hey!
-表情也很可怕 -別說了
Go! Now!
快給我去發問卷
Okay.
是
Excuse me, this is a questionnaire about your lunch.
不好意思 我們在做有關午餐的問卷
Could you answer it?
能請您幫個忙嗎？
We're doing a questionnaire. Are you temp workers?
你們是派遣員工嗎？
What did you eat for lunch yesterday?
你昨天午餐吃什麼呢？
Thank you.
謝謝
Excuse me.
不好意思
It's a questionnaire about lunch.
我們在做午餐相關的問卷
Temp's Lunch Box?
派遣便當嗎？
Interesting.
好有趣
Chief!
主任
What are you eating?
你在吃什麼？
Take more.
多吃點
Please answer this.
麻煩您填寫問卷
- Okay. - Can I take a picture of you?
能讓我拍張照嗎？
- Sure. - Thank you.
-可以的 -不好意思
Excuse me.
謝謝
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Here.
好
How is it?
醬汁豬排怎麼樣？
Can this be mass produced?
這能夠大量生產嗎？
Yes, it can.
沒問題
I'll be back.
那我繼續去發了
"Questionnaire"
（問卷統計）
- Mori. - Yes.
-森 -是
It's six now, you can go home.
已經六點了，今天先下班吧
I'll stay a bit longer.
沒關係，我再多發一點…
Excuse me.
不好意思
This is a questionnaire about your lunch.
我們在做有關午餐的問卷
Can you answer it?
能請您幫個忙嗎？
Excuse me.
抱歉
Can you please answer our questionnaire?
能請您幫忙填個問卷嗎？
Thank you.
麻煩您了
Please help us with our questionnaire.
麻煩幫我們填寫問卷
Mori?
森小姐？
Hitotsugi!
一木先生
Six hundred people have answered.
收集六百份了
Four hundred more to go.
還有四百份嗎？
Hi there.
你們好
Hitotsugi.
一木先生
If you guys are doing this, please let me be part of it.
里中主任，這種事就交給我吧
We're doing a skill-up training at our agency today.
我們公司今天剛好 要辦技職研習
We need your feedback to make our lunchboxes.
我們想要採納各位的意見 做出優秀的便當
Thank you.
麻煩大家了
Lunch Box of the temps,
源自派遣員工的點子
by the temps, and for the temps.
為了派遣員工 而誕生的派遣便當
Please spend some time answering the questionnaire.
請各位幫忙寫問卷
Thank you for your cooperation.
謝謝你們的幫忙
Thank you.
謝謝
Are you a temp, too?
你也是派遣員工嗎？
Yes.
對
This was her idea.
這是她的點子
I'm excited to see how the lunch box turns out.
我很期待會做出什麼樣的便當
Thank you.
謝謝
I like that it's written in katakana.
派遣寫成片假名很可愛呢
I was the one who changed it.
這是我想的點子喔
Thank you.
謝謝各位
You have a puppy?
您有養小狗啊？
Speaking of puppies,
說到小狗
I have a friend who looks like a lost puppy when he's down.
我有個朋友的眼神 也很像迷路的小狗
Like what?
是怎樣的眼神呢？
Like this.
就像這樣
Oh wow.
天啊
That's so cute.
好可愛
You think it's cute?
很可愛嗎？
We have a troublesome temp worker.
我們公司有個囂張的派遣員工
Turtleneck is always insulting me.
他一直被那位套頭毛衣女欺負
Turtleneck?
套頭毛衣女？
What's wrong?
東海林，你怎麼了？
Say something funny.
再多說點有趣的話題吧
Okay.
這樣啊
Something funny?
有趣的…
Oh, the president.
董事長
Welcome.
歡迎
You're alone tonight?
今天一個人嗎？
That's rare. come in.
真難得，請坐
Please leave.
歡迎回來
Wow.
真是的
So scary.
好嚇人
Why? So sudden.
怎麼突然這樣
I have a scary face. Problem?
我的表情很恐怖，有問題嗎？
Alright.
等等
Let's not fight today.
今天就別吵了吧
I was on a date with that girl
我剛從相親回來
and I feel happy now.
現在正幸福呢
You went on a date without straightening your hair?
沒有把頭髮燙直就去相親
As I said before--
就說了別再提到直髮
Reiko would never say mean things like that.
麗子小姐她
Reiko is the president's daughter.
麗子小姐是董事長千金
Is he here to brag about his date?
他是來炫耀的嗎？
If I marry her,
只要跟她結婚
I'll be a winner for sure.
我就會變成勝利組了
You're right, except for your headpiece.
對啊，除了你的假髮
This is my natural hair.
這是我天生的頭髮
They say rich people don't fight.
有句話說「有錢人不會吵架」
Ken's not here to stop me though.
今天會勸架的小賢也不在
His hair is straight, and so is his heart.
那個人無論是髮型 或是內心都很正直
You know what?
你啊
You said that you don't take sides.
明明說不會成為任何人的夥伴
But you're on Ken's side.
卻很願意替小賢出口氣呢
Compared to you, Chief Satonaka
里中主任
is better as a person.
他的人品要好得多了
Keep talking.
繼續說啊
I'm sure you have more.
你有其他話想說吧
The director's suck-up.
部長的馬屁精
Interceptor.
愛搶功勞
An idea thief.
愛抄襲的自然捲
Actually, I've heard enough.
還是算了吧
Oh yeah.
對了
I have one compliment for you.
但唯有一點值得稱讚
What?
是什麼？
That is...
那就是
that you care about your friends a lot.
替朋友著想的心
But right now,...
但是現在
you've even lost that.
連這個優點都沒了
But I'm a winner.
但我是人生勝利組
That's right.
沒錯
I'll tell you this.
我話說在前面
You can't be arrogant much longer.
你也只有現在能囂張了
The gap is widening.
我們之間的落差會越來越大
Even with your skills,
無論你有多少專長
your future as a temp is dark.
派遣員的未來都很黑暗
I don't need you to be worried about me.
這輪不到你來擔心
Hey, wait.
站住
What did you come here for?
你到底來做什麼的？
To talk about our future.
我是來討論和你的未來的
About the gap, again?
又要說我們的落差了嗎？
No, that's not it.
不是這樣的
I...
我…
I think I'll decline this arranged marriage.
想要拒絕部長介紹的婚事
You don't mean that.
別說這些違心之論
For someone who likes being tied to the company,
對最喜歡攀著公司的你來說
it's the perfect offer.
這是再適合不過的好姻緣
True.
的確
You're right.
是很適合
You...
你啊
you've always won by clinging onto Director Kirishima.
是因為巴著桐島部長 才能在今天勝出
If you go against him,
如果你違逆他
you won't survive at that company.
在那間公司也待不下去了
That's also true.
這也對
Going against the boss
違逆上司
is something a loser does.
是失敗組才會做的事
That's right.
也對
After all,...
到最後
you'll marry her because your director told you to.
你只會對部長唯命是從 跟對方結婚
That's annoying.
氣死人了
A temp can't tell me who to marry.
憑什麼一個派遣員 要左右我的婚姻
Why is an employee asking a temp for advice about marriage?
那為什麼一個正職員工 要來找派遣員討論？
That is...
這是因為…
You exhaust me.
我累了
No, listen to me.
別這樣，你聽我說
You're the one I want to marry.
我真正想結婚的對象是你
Because of the arrange marriage,
我還有那樁相親
I want your answer quickly.
請快點給我答覆
That's crazy, like your hair.
要開玩笑就對捲捲頭開吧
I'm serious.
我是認真的
Check, please.
麻煩結帳
It's fine.
那個啊…
- Don't worry today. - Here.
今天就不用了
I'm a winner.
因為我是勝利組
Haruko.
等等…春子前輩
- What will you do? - What an idiot.
該怎麼辦啊
Thirty one more days to go.
還有31天
Good morning.
早安
Please wait.
請等一下
Shoji.
東海林
Yes?
是
It's the president calling.
董事長親自打電話來了
Do you want to take this?
你直接接吧
Please give me a second.
請等一下，部長
Hey.
喂
Give me an answer.
快告訴我答覆吧
- Answer. - Yes?
-答覆 -是？
Not that kind of answer.
不是這種普通的答覆
About last night.
是昨晚的…
- Shoji? - Hurry.
-東海林先生？ -快點
Shoji.
東海林
What are you doing?
-是 -你在做什麼？
Okay.
我來了
She gave me feedback.
他來問你的答覆了
What?
咦？
She said, perfect.
萬事OK
You'll accept it, right? I already told him so.
你也贊成吧？ 那就這樣回答他吧
Good job.
幹得好
Thank you.
謝謝
Keep it up,...
保持這個狀態
and win that presentation tomorrow.
明天的發表一定要贏
Yes.
是
He couldn't be happier.
部長竟然那麼開心
Shoji.
東海林
Congratulations.
恭喜你
You're going straight to success.
公司員工的前途一片光明呢
I'll follow you for life.
我會一輩子跟隨東海林主任
Shoji.
你真會巴結
Tomorrow is the presentation.
明天就是最終發表了
Let's do this.
打起精神來
Yeah!
是
- Good morning. - It looks like it's a done deal.
好像決定了
Is that true?
是這樣啊？
The most requested
最多人希望的
is tasty rice.
是「米飯的美味程度」
Yeah, Japanese people love white rice, after all.
沒錯，日本人就是要吃白米飯
Many like brown rice, too.
糙米也很有人氣呢
Omelette was the most liked among side dishes.
最受歡迎的菜色是玉子燒
They would spend up to 500 yen.
價格剛好落在五百圓
It can't be more than 500 yen.
我以為會再更高呢
Everyone.
各位
You all did a great job.
真的辛苦大家了
Nice job.
主任也辛苦了
Hitotsugi,
一木先生
thank you for your help.
謝謝你的幫忙
No problem.
哪裡
It really helped us.
真的幫大忙了
I'm glad to help.
我才要說謝謝
I've never seen a temp's idea being selected in my entire career.
沒想到派遣員工的點子 竟然能進到社內競賽的決賽
I'm proud of you, Mori.
我也很榮幸呢，森
The company treats it as Chief Shoji's project.
雖然在公司裡 企劃是掛東海林主任的名字
Is that so?
是這樣啊？
- Not Chief Satonaka's? - No.
不是里中主任？
- Chief Shoji? - Yes.
-是東海林主任？ -對
Here it is.
好，完成了
Mori.
森
You're so good at drawing.
你好會畫畫
You're a good artist.
好有天分
It's pretty.
好漂亮
- It looks tasty. - It's our lunch box.
-看起來很好吃 -這是青椒肉絲便當
Did you draw one, too?
你也畫了嗎？
Look at that.
這幅畫
Did you draw it seriously?
你是認真畫的嗎？
It's like my daughter's drawing.
跟我女兒畫的有得拚
That's her weakness?
發現意外的弱點了
That's our important questionnaire.
大前小姐，那是很重要的問卷
Please calm down, it's fine.
冷靜點，沒事的
This won't be in your resume.
這不會寫進你的經歷的
I'll go deliver this.
我把這些送過去了
Thank you.
一路小心
Alright.
他走了
What am I doing?
這是我該做的事嗎？
"Temp's Lunch Box"
（派遣便當）
"Shoji Takeshi"
（東海林武）
Please check this, sir.
部長，請您確認一下
Excuse me.
辛苦了
What's up, Ken?
小賢，怎麼了？
Here you go.
這些
Feedback from the 1,000 temps
是一千名派遣員工的問卷
and the analysis results.
還有分析結果
- You really asked 1,000 people? - Yeah.
你們真的收集了一千份啊？
Use this for the presentation.
想說明天發表應該能派上用場
This is the kind of lunch box temp workers are looking for.
派遣員工
It's so idealistic.
小賢，這太理想化了
We can't achieve this price.
這個價格是不可能的
Our division decided to collaborate with lunch box store chains
營業部要和連鎖便當店合作
and let them figure everything out.
菜單和做法都交給他們
That'd be just like a regular lunch box,
那就和普通的便當一樣了
But this isn't realistic.
但這太不切實際了
That's enough, Satonaka.
里中，夠了吧
Sir...
部長
Go back to your section
你回自己的部門
and work.
好好工作吧
See you tomorrow.
辛苦了
Omae.
大前小姐
Yes?
有事嗎？
The questionnaire...
那些
they didn't take it.
沒有被採用
I wanted to make our customers happy
我們是為了看到客人的笑容
so I made the questionnaire.
才做了那些問卷
But they said it wasn't realistic.
結果被說不切實際
Okay. So?
然後呢？
What was I doing?
我到底都在幹嘛呢？
Everyone worked hard...
拼命地做那些
and I feel bad for them.
對行銷課的大家也很過意不去
More than anything...
更重要的
I feel bad for the 1,000 temp workers that we talked to.
是對不起
You're always like this.
你一直都是這樣呢
You didn't do anything...
明明沒做錯
but you always feel guilty.
卻說對不起別人
All you do is being depressed.
垂頭喪氣的
You haven't done anything yet.
我們還沒開始動手吧
They said that it was unrealistic,
被說不切實際
so you'll just give it up?
就要放棄了嗎？
If it's unrealistic,...
這種事
then make it realistic.
只要變成現實就好了
Alright.
好
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll see you tomorrow.
部長，我先離開了
See you.
辛苦了
Don't be late tomorrow.
明天可別遲到
Of course.
是
He's unbelievable.
那傢伙真是的
I'll talk to him.
我會再好好說說他的
Shoji.
東海林
Yes?
是
Satonaka will be transferred.
里中會被踢走
He's not contributing to our sales department.
他沒辦法成為營業部的戰力
He'll go to our subsidiary.
把他調到分公司吧
Sir...
部長
Satonaka will be transferred.
里中會被踢走
He's not contributing to our sales department.
他沒辦法成為營業部的戰力
He'll go to our subsidiary.
把他調到分公司吧
Oh.
什麼？
You're still here?
東海林先生還在啊
You want coffee?
要喝咖啡嗎？
Shoji?
東海林先生？
I'm sorry, Ken.
小賢，抱歉了
About the questionnaire?
問卷的事嗎？
It's fine.
沒關係的
I know that 500 yen isn't realistic,
畢竟五百圓太困難了
but with reasonable producers...
除非找到有良心的廠商
Please stop now.
別做這些了
I knew it.
我很明白
I knew you would...
小賢你
let me have your project.
一定會把企劃讓給我
You've always been like this.
因為一直都是這樣的
Ever since we joined the company,...
從進公司之後
you let me take the credit.
你一直都把功勞讓給我
What's going on?
東海林先生，怎麼了？
What happened?
發生什麼事了？
Why are you worried about me?
為什麼要這麼擔心我？
Why aren't you angry with me?
為什麼你都不發火？
That's why the director...
就是這樣部長才…
What is it?
什麼？
We've always worked under our director.
我一直跟在部長後頭做事
If he fired us,...
要是被他拋棄了
we'd have nowhere to go.
就沒有生存之地了
But...
但是…
this is the only way I know.
我也只做得到這些事
You should be better than this.
你要再更積極點啊
I can't.
我做不到
I can't be like you, Shoji.
我無法成為東海林先生
You're right.
也對
Shoji?
東海林先生
Why are you so upset?
你在煩什麼？
You can talk to me about anything.
有煩惱就跟我說吧
I'm so sick of this.
我已經受夠了
I'm sick of stupid people-pleasers like you.
我沒法再和 你這種濫好人當朋友了
I finally understand why you take temps' side.
我終於知道派遣員工 為什麼會站在你那邊了
Because you're a loser like them.
你跟他們一樣，都是喪家之犬
Shoji.
東海林先生
saved by Omae in a pinch.
大前小姐不也替你 解決過危機嗎？
You don't get to call her a loser.
你沒資格說她是喪家之犬
Take advantage of temps, and then throw them away.
派遣員工是利用完 就可以丟的棋子
Are you serious?
你是認真的嗎？
Yes.
對
You know...
對我來說
I don't care about Temp's Lunch Box.
派遣便當怎樣都好
Thanks to you, I'll be promoted again.
多虧你們，我又能更往上爬了
No hard feelings.
我覺得也不賴啊
It's your fault that you're used as a stepping stone.
是被當墊腳石的人自己不好
Finally, you're angry.
你終於生氣了呢
By the way,...
順便問你一句
do you like Turtleneck?
小賢你喜歡套頭毛衣女嗎？
What if I do?
那又怎樣？
I...
我
I like her.
喜歡她
I knew it.
果然是這樣
Why didn't you say anything?
為什麼一直沉默不說？
Why did you say that you'd back me up?
為什麼還要替我加油？
That's the part I hate the most about you.
你就是這點讓人最不爽
Why do you always let me have everything?
什麼都願意讓給我
Shoji.
東海林先生
You're being easy on me.
為什麼要手下留情？
It's not like you.
這真不像你
If you want to fight, do it seriously.
要打就認真打啊
You!
可惡
We shouldn't have done this.
早知道就不打了
I had no idea you're this strong, Ken.
小賢你竟然這麼強
Shoji, you are...
是東海林先生
just too weak.
你太爛了
What?
說什麼
Ouch.
好痛
I've never seen this place this way
都過了八年 我還是第一次看到這種景象
Just...
我們兩人
what are we doing here?
到底在幹嘛？
There is someone else that we should be beating up.
明明還有其他想揍飛的傢伙
What?
你是在說誰啊？
That darn director, Kirishima!
部長算什麼
The company!
公司又算什麼
Shoji...
東海林先生
you sound...
你這樣
like an drunk man.
你這只是普通的醉話罷了
This isn't good.
這下慘了
Kirishima will yell at me tomorrow.
明天要被部長罵了
Shoji.
東海林先生
You'll give a presentation like that?
你明天要帶著那張臉發表嗎？
You, too.
你才是
Look at your face.
還有臉說別人啊
This isn't good.
這下糟糕了
Alright.
好
Please head back.
請回去
"Haruko Omae"
（春子前輩）
Hello?
喂
This is the first time
我還是第一次接到 春子前輩的電話
What's going on so late?
這個時間是發生什麼事了？
Come over now.
別管了，馬上過來
Wash the vegetables.
你去洗菜
Sure.
是
Burdock roots, 10 grams.
牛蒡是十公克
Seven kilo calories.
七大卡
Fifty grams of eggs.
雞蛋50公克
Seventy five kilo calories.
75大卡
Fifty five grams of mackerel.
鯖魚55公克
We throw 40 percent of it, so 80 kilo calories.
廢棄率有4成，所以是80大卡
Eighty kilo calories.
80大卡
Here you go.
好了
By the way, as for mackerel,
對了，鯖魚…
it was ranked 18th and they prefer grilled with salt.
是第18名，大家都喜歡鹽烤的
Mackerel cooked with miso is low calories and well balanced.
味噌鯖魚熱量低，也比較營養 而且含有大量大豆異黃酮
It's perfect for temps.
這是最適合派遣員工的菜色
We can't lose that.
這道菜絕對不能排除
Okay.
是
It's done.
完成了
It looks great.
好好吃的樣子
"Questionnaire on marriage"
（關於結婚的問卷）
"Chief Takeshi Shoji"
（東海林武）
Good morning.
早安
What happened to your face?
主任，你的臉怎麼了？
I was in a fight.
跟人打了一架
A fight?
打架？
What's this?
這是？
This cost 1,000 yen a piece.
一份便當大約一千圓
It's your job to reduce the cost to 500 yen.
將這壓到五百圓就是你的工作
"Temp's Lunch Box"
（派遣便當）
Shoji's late.
東海林先生好慢
What is he doing?
他在做什麼
Call him.
快打電話給他
Okay.
是
What happened?
東海林先生，你怎麼了？
It's a big presentation day.
重要的發表日
What happened to your face?
你的臉是怎麼回事？
Sir.
部長
Good morning.
早安
Everyone is waiting.
大家等很久了
Hurry.
動作快
Chief, we've just received here.
主任，這是剛才收到的
A lunch box?
-便當嗎？ -對
They said it's for you.
有人要我交給東海林主任
This is the best Temp's Lunch Box.
這是最棒的派遣便當
If you think you can match this, bring it on.
你做得到的話就做看看
"Questionnaire on marriage"
（關於結婚的問卷）
"Would you like to marry Takeshi Shoji? - No."
（你想和東海林武結婚嗎？）
"I don't want to marry the temps' enemy."
（我不想和 派遣員工的敵人結婚）
"Write down your phone number"
（請寫下你的手機號碼）
For S&amp;F's 80th anniversary,
接著進行S&amp;F公司80週年
we'd like to begin the final presentation.
社內企劃募集競賽最終發表
First is Temp's Lunch Box from Sales Department.
首先是營業部的「派遣便當」
The planner of the project, Chief Shoji will present.
有請企劃發起人東海林主任
Shoji.
東海林
Chief Shoji?
東海林主任？
Chief.
主任
I'm very sorry,...
非常抱歉
but I can't present this.
我無法發表
Because Temp's Lunch Box...
派遣便當
was not what I proposed.
並不是我的企劃
What?
怎麼回事？
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Take that back.
快收回你的話
I won't.
恕我拒絕
Sir.
部長
Chief Shoji.
東海林主任
Please explain what's going on.
請你好好解釋清楚
This project...
這份企劃
belongs to Kensuke Satonaka...
是里中賢介
and Marketing Section.
和行銷課的企劃
- What? - Director Kirishima?
-什麼？ -桐島
Explain.
為什麼是行銷課？
What is he talking about?
那怎麼會變成販賣二課
What's happening here?
桐島部長，這是怎麼回事？
What should we do now?
怎麼了？
Let's start our lunch box taste test.
現在開始進行試吃大會
Great.
是
Let's eat.
我開動了
Haruko cooked that mackerel.
那條鯖魚是春子前輩釣到的
Really?
這樣啊
You can't draw, but you have many other talents.
雖然你很不會畫畫
The fish market wasn't open, so I went fishing, so?
因為河岸還沒營業
Thank you.
謝謝
It's good.
很好吃
You said it so softly, I couldn't hear.
你說得那麼小聲 害我嚇一大跳
"I don't want to marry the temps' enemy"
（我不想和 派遣員工的敵人結婚）
She thinks a temp can do this to me?
區區一個派遣員工 少那麼囂張了